I get asked this question on a regular
basis, so I thought I'd finally update
on my supplement routine. If you don't
know who I am, my name is Nick. I earned
my PhD in molecular medicine and I
analyze studies for a living. So, I've
chosen these supplements because they
have a ton of scientific evidence behind
them and they serve my goals well. First
thing, I wake up and I drizzle a little
creatine on my
eyeballs. All right, I'll be serious.
Yes, creatine is a favorite of mine. Who
would have thought? I've only released
the most videos and analyses on creatine
of any supplement. Creatine is
beneficial for my muscle performance
when I'm hidden at iron, and it also
improves mental performance. It's an
incredible molecule, and I'll link
videos to some of my analyses on the
topic in the pinned comment. Also,
there's no evidence that it causes hair
loss. I have a video on the science of
that. And it also doesn't harm the
kidneys. have a video on the science of
that. I'll link both in the pin comment,
too. For a laugh, there's a comment
someone posted several days ago under
one of my videos. It's especially
comical considering that I wrote uh my
one book on that singular molecule.
Anyway, I take five grams per day,
sometimes more. Uh I'm not loyal to any
brand. You could call me a rogue agent
for the cheapest price. I take creatine
monohydrate, and I take it whenever my
brain kicks in to remind me. My second
supplement is omega-3s. Again, a lot of
evidence behind them for the heart and
the brain. I have videos on both from
the clinical data to the mechanistic
data pinned below as well. I don't take
much, just one pill and I'm currently
using Life Extension. But again, I have
no affiliation to that brand. They just
put a cool 5 mil in my bank account and
wrote me saying, "Do the right thing or
else." Anyway, great brand. I suppose I
should disclose that was a joke.
Sometimes I make jokes like being
sponsored by Pepsi and people will
actually think that I'm being serious.
It's happened many times. I am sponsored
by no one except the Physionic Insiders.
Come on, that was an app transition. I
am a crowdfunded dude. If you like my
work and care to support me, that's the
best place to do it. The link's in the
description. It keeps big Pepsi out of
these videos. But this isn't a charity.
I actually offer a lot of value over
there. Or at least I like to think that
I do as a oneman operation. Releasing
two to three research reviews per week,
two to three videos per week, a monthly
podcast, live sessions to discuss
science together, and more. Anyway,
check it out. But, you know, no
pressure. You skipped too far. Hold on.
We have to wait for the people who
skipped my insider advertisement to come
back. Maybe I should just like put
something on the screen so that they
know where to tune in again. Here we
go. The third supplement is a
multivitamin. I usually break these in
half because my nutrition is quite
nutritious. Don't ask me what it is. I
make a point not to say as I've seen
plenty of other health influencer types
that I genuinely respect to mention what
they eat and then everything that they
say gets ignored from that point onward
by some. A shame, but that's the
reality. People are always looking for
ways to dismiss a person's
interpretation of the data and dismiss
them as biased. Anyway, again, I just
take a one a day, half a multivitamin.
As a kid, I used to eat those Flintstone
vitamins, but ever since I grew up into
a big boy, I had to learn how to swallow
pills like a real
man. I may switch to gummies. The fourth
supplement is lutein and zeazanthin.
Technically two molecules, but they're
packaged as one. Again, there's some
great evidence behind them, at least for
your eyes. I don't know if you've
noticed, but I wear glasses and I'm
constantly on the computer doing work
for you guys. So, it's just a good way
for me to keep my eye health in check. I
also do some basic eye exercises
whenever I remember, which is about once
every 4 months. I take one pill from a
life extension again. Have I mentioned
how great they are? Again, unaffiliated.
I also take collagen peptides. I use 10
grams again from whatever brand is the
cheapest. And I largely take it for my
skin. And I imagine that as I get older,
it'll probably or hopefully aid in joint
health as well. Oh, in addition, in
colder months only, I take the lowest
dose that I can find of vitamin D3. I'm
a sunscreen fanatic to keep me looking
35, although I'm 94. And I also have a
contempt for cancer. As a result, my
blood vitamin D levels have been known
to drop during that time. That's why I
supplement. Someone probably already
wrote how sunlight is good for you.
Sunscreen is toxic and uh five billion
IUs of vitamin D will turn you into a
god. Uh if you could uh do me a favor,
look at your keyboard, locate the
backspace button, and click it to empty,
I'd appreciate it. On to the next one.
The next supplement
is nothing. That's it. Sometimes I'll
take some rodeiola rosia when I'm a bit
stressed, but
otherwise the that's all
folks. In the end, I cover a lot of
supplements in my analyses because
people want to hear more about
supplements than anything else. And I do
think that supplements can help. But
although I've covered so many like
glycine, torine, lion's mane,
bourberine, and many more, the reality
is that supplements aren't going to
change the world for many people. And
supplement stacks will depend on need.
For example, I wouldn't tell a person on
a plant-based diet that consumes a lot
of kale to consume lutein and zeazanthin
because they already get a lot. Or if I
were pre-diabetic, I'd probably add
something like curcumin. Or if I were a
triathlete, I'd likely add electrolytes.
Or if I had high blood pressure, I'd add
a partial potassium chloride salt. The
point is, the point being there's a lot
of nuance on the individual level. So,
while yes, I think that creatine,
omega-3s, and possibly a multivitamin
would offer small to moderate benefit to
almost everyone, these supplements
aren't rules. You can add or subtract
based on what you deem fits your
lifestyle and your goals. I still think
that exercise, nutrition, stress
management, social interactions, and
sleep are the biggest pillars to
successfully keeping your body healthy.
And if people want more supplement
videos, I'll just keep cranking them
out. In fact, I have a list of all the
supplements that I've covered, doses,
and which ones would be best in
particular needs in my Aphysiic Insiders
membership. Just another reason to join.
Anyway, I cover more on supplements
right here as well. Thanks for tuning
in.
I introduced the end screen
prematurely, so I kind of have to
awkwardly stand here until you click on
one. Oh, I know. I'll add
this. And that's all, folks.